deep model에서 텍스트를 어떻게
다루는지에 대해서 논의해보겠습니다.
Let's talk about how to
handle text in a deep model.
당신이 문서를 분류하기를
원하다고 상상해보세요.
Imagine that you want
to classify a document.
문서가 정치, 사업에 대한 것인가요?
아니면, 과학에 대해서인가요?
Is it talking about politics,
or business, or science maybe?
당신은 그 문서에 포함된
단어들을 보고 있을 것입니다.
You're going to have to look
at the words in that document
어떤 종류의 문서인지 알아내기 위해서...
to figure that out.
포함된 단어들이 정말로 어렵습니다.
Words are really difficult.
단어들중에서 대부분이
당신이 보지 못한 것들입니다.
There are lots of them and
most of them you never, ever see.
당신이 거의 보지 못한 단어들이 실제로
가장 중요한 것이 되는 경향이 있습니다.
In fact the ones that you rarely see,
tend to be the most important ones.
만약 문서에 duh(감탄사)가 포함되어 있다면,
당신은 어떤 종류의 문서인지 전혀 알 수가 없을 것입니다.
If you know that your document contains
duh, you don't know much at all.
그러나 retinopathy(망막병증)이란
단어가 있다면,
But if you know that it
contains retinopathy,
아마도 의학 문서라고
알 수 있습니다.
you know that it's probably
a medical document.
Retinopathy은 영어에서 0.0001%의 빈도로
나타납니다.
Retinopathy appears with
a frequency of 0.0001% in English.
이 단어는 이전에 당신이 결코
보지 못한 단어일 수 있습니다.
It's even possible that you've never
seen that word yourself before.
deep learning에서는,
그런 드문 사건은 문제가 되지 않습니다.
For deep learning,
rare events like that are a problem.
우리는 학습시킬 예제를 많이
가지고 있습니다.
We like to have lots of training
examples to learn from.